In this course, you will learn how to wrangle and model massive datasets with Pi Spark,
which is a Python library for interacting with Spark.
We have divided the materials into four main parts.
In the first lesson,
you will learn about big data and how Spark fits into the big data ecosystem.
In lesson two, it will be practice processing and cleaning
datasets to get comfortable with Spark's SQL and dataframe APIs.
In the third lesson,
we will cover how to debug and optimize your Spark code when running on a cluster.
Finally, in lesson four,
you will use Spark's Machine Learning Library to train machine learning models at scale.
Once you master these four necessary pieces,
you'll build a Spark program that solves a real-world problem predicting
the turn of users for a music streaming service like Spotify or Pandora.
You will have the opportunity to go above and beyond with this project.
The provided dataset has plenty of options for creative feature engineering and modeling.
We're glad that you're here and we hope you'll enjoy
learning about how to scale up your data analysis,
and machine learning projects. Let's get started