Imagine you are working
on the data team for a popular digital music service similar to Spotify or Pandora.
Menus of users stream their favorite songs to your service every day either using
the free tier that place advertisements between
the songs or using the premium subscription model,
where they stream music as free but pay a monthly flat rate.
Users can upgrade, downgrade,
or cancel their service at any time.
So, it's crucial to make sure your users love the service.
Every time a user interacts with the service while they're playing songs, logging out,
like in a song with a thumbs up, hearing an ad,
or downgrading their service, it generates data.
All this data contains the key insights for
keeping your users happy and helping your business thrive.
It's your job on the data team to predict which users are at risk to
churn either downgrading from premium
to free tier or cancelling their service altogether.
If you can accurately identify these users before they leave,
your business can offer them discounts and incentives,
potentially saving your business millions in revenue.
To tackle this project,
we have provided you with a large dataset that contains the events David just described.
You will need to load,
explorer, and clean this dataset with Spark.
Based on your explanation,
you will create features and build models with Spark to
predict which users were churn from your digital music service.
This project is all about demonstrating mastery of
Spark scalable data manipulation and machine learning.
After completing this project,
you'll have built a useful model with a massive dataset.
You'll be able to apply the same skills with Spark to
wrangle data and build models in your role as a data scientist.